Jacob Blakely | Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

I specialize in making complex things simple. I take great joy in crafting and delivering elegant software solutions across the entire stack, with a particular passion for the web and the command line. Experienced in leading and contributing to remote software teams to ship products to millions of users. Comfortable in customer-facing roles. Excellent communicator.

SKILLS -

Languages Typescript, Node.js, Python, Lua, Go, CSS, SQL, Shell

Frameworks React, Redux, Jest, Next.js, Django, REST Framework, Kubernetes

Other API Design and Development, Webhooks, Technical Documentation, AWS.

> GraphQL, Database Architecture, Linux Administration, Microservices, Git, Open Source Development, Customer Support, Responsive Design, CI/CD

EXPERIENCE -

Code Kirei LLC | Freelance Engineer and Consultant

2014 - Present

Providing web-focused consulting and software development services.

Blakely Real Estate | Co-Owner and Agent

2022 - 2023

- Introduced systems automation to significantly reduce operational overhead
- Designed and implemented new marketing channels to diversify client pipelines

Zapier | Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

2016 - 2022

- Created internal chrome extension to dramatically improve customer support efficiency
- Co-lead skunkworks team that developed visionary product prototypes; many features made it onto long-term product roadmaps that drive millions in ARR
- Co-created webhook ingestion microservice that handles millions of daily requests
- Embedded in core frontend team to refactor critical legacy components; significantly reduced frontend bundle size and build complexity
- Created internal blogging platform that was one of three pillars of internal communication at company; scaled to hundreds of internal users
- Participated in hiring panels for multiple engineer roles as team scaled from 15 to 100+
- Trained many hires on backend systems and tech support rotations
- Mentored multiple early-stage engineers one-on-one who went on to be key contributors

Translations.com | Client Services

2012 - 2013

Managed full product lifecycle for client accounts worth over a million dollars in annual revenue.

EDUCATION —

University of Oregon, Clark Honors College

2007 - 2012

Bachelor of Arts, Cum Laude | Business Administration, Japanese, Economics